他们非常高大，有时身高2米以上
They're quite large. Seven feet tall is not unusual.
动作很快，非常强壮
They're extremely fast and strong.
上尉
Lieutenant.
别犯错，他们可能会非常危险
Make no mistake, they can be highly dangerous.
科普兰人的基本武器：科里镖
The Capellan's basic weapon: The kligat.
100米以内
At any distance up to 100 yards,
足以抗衡手持相位枪的人类
they can make it almost as effective against a man as a phaser.
除此之外，还有各种类型的剑和刀
In addition to this, an assortment of swords and knives.
舰桥发来的，舰长
Call from the Bridge, captain.
舰桥，我是舵手
Bridge. Helm, sir.
收到，苏鲁先生请讲
Yes, Mr. Sulu. Report.
现在处于标准轨道，已经锁定他们的营房
Now in standard orbit, sir. I've pinpointed their encampment below.
很好，准备好传送室
Very good. Have the Transporter Room stand by.
是，舰长
Aye, sir.
你在这个星球驻扎多久了，医生？
How long were you stationed on the planet, Doctor?
几个月而已
Only a few months.
我们发现他们对医疗援助完全没有兴趣
We found them totally uninterested in medical aid or hospitals.
他们认为强者才能生存下来
They believe that only the strong should survive.
各位有什么看法？
Analysis, gentlemen?
一般在这种情况下
Ordinarily, under these circumstances,
我会建议派遣大量武装人员登陆
I would recommend a large well-armed landing party.
但是现在这种情况，我们去的人越多
Yes, but in this case, with the more people we take down,
就越有可能触犯他们的某条禁忌
the greater chance we have of violating one of their taboos.
同意，一旦他们认为我们是来炫耀武力的
Agreed. Once they've got it into their heads we're showing force,
就不会再记得什么采矿协议了
you can forget them signing any mining treaty.
很好，史考特，你来指挥
Very well. Scotty, you're in command.
记住，这一区域曾观察到有克林贡人出没
Bear in mind that the Klingons have been sighted in this sector.
我们去下面谈判的时候
While we're negotiating there, we don't want the Enterprise
- 可不希望进取号出什么问题 - 是，舰长，我们会保持警惕
- to become an incident up here. - Aye, sir. We'll keep on our toes.
站住！
Halt!
你们是从地球来的？
You are of the Earth vessel?
我是寇克舰长
I am Captain Kirk.
我们手无寸铁，为和平而来
We come with open hearts and hands.
- 克林贡人！ - 格兰特，别！
- A Klingon! - Grant, no!
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：诺阿诺阿
校对：喜马拉雅
第二季第十一集
「星期五的孩子」
舰长日志，星历3497.2
Captain's log, stardate 3497.2.
科普兰IV星球
Planet Capella IV.
在这里发现了大量托帕林
The rare mineral topaline
这是一种对小行星殖民地生命维持系统
vital to the life support systems of planetoid colonies
至关重要的稀有矿物
has been discovered in abundance here.
我们的任务是，争取达成采矿协议
Our mission: Obtain a mining agreement.
但是我们发现有一名克林贡特工捷足先登
But we've discovered a Klingon agent has preceded us to the planet,
这一发现导致我们一名船员牺牲
a discovery which has cost the life of one of my crewmen.
我不知道我们之间有任何战争，舰长
I am unaware of any state of war between our peoples, captain.
吉姆
Jim.
还是说你们有规定要杀死任何视线内的克林贡人？
Or is it your policy to kill Klingons on sight?
他还很年轻…
He was young...
…经验不足
...and inexperienced.
马布知道克林贡人
Does Maab know that the Klingons are our sworn enemies
是我们的死敌吗？
by their own words?
我们只知道他们也愿意花大价钱换我们的石头
We understand only that he also offers things of value for our rocks.
而且还把自己的武器和其他设备交给了我们
And he has freely handed us his weapons and other devices.
你们也会这么做吗？
Will you do the same?
让我联系我的星舰，通知他们…
Let me call my ship and inform them...
攻击我们的村庄？
To bring down an attack upon their village?
我告诉过你，马布
It is as I told you, Maab.
地球人害怕诚实的讨价还价
Earthmen fear to bargain honestly.
你们会把武器交出来吗？
Will you hand us your weapons?
他们非常守信，尤其诚实
"So they keep their word scrupulously. They're unusually honest."
在会议室时你是这么说的吧，医生？
Is that what I heard you say in the Briefing Room, Doctor?
是，我提到过
Yes, I mentioned that.
他也提到过他们会非常危险
He also mentioned that they can be highly dangerous.
如果对他们撒谎的话
Dangerous if lied to.
如果违反他们的习俗的话
If their customs are violated.
我们没有撒谎，也没有违反他们的习俗
Well, we lied to no one, Doctor. We violated no customs.
你来跟我解释一下，为什么我的船员死了
Perhaps you'll explain to me why one of my men is dead.
因为他拿武器指着对方的另一位客人
Because he was drawing a weapon on another of their guests.
格兰特抬头
Grant looked up,
看见一个克林贡人，作出了完全出于本能的行为
saw a Klingon, made a purely instinctive defensive move.
克林贡人在
What's a Klingon doing down here
你那十分诚实守信的朋友这里做什么？
among your scrupulously honest friends anyway?
吉姆，我知道失去一名船员你很难过
Look, Jim, I know what it means to you to lose a crewman.
这里只有一名
That's only one down, Doctor.
还有400多名船员在轨道上的星舰里呢
There's over 400 more up there in orbit.
如果这里有一名克林贡人
And if there's a Klingon down here...
那肯定某处有一艘克林贡人的飞船
...there might be a Klingon ship up there somewhere.
史考特先生
Mr. Scott...
传感器上有东西出现了
...picking up something on the sensors, sir.
看起来像一艘飞船
Seems to be another ship.
放到显示器上看看
Let's put it on the screen.
就在我们传感器扫描范围的边缘
It's just at the edge of our sensor range, sir.
很难得到精确读数
Hard to get an exact reading.
你觉得是克林贡飞船？
You think it's a Klingon ship?
谁还会跟星舰玩捉迷藏呢？
Who else would be playing cat and mouse with a starship?
距离太远，它也奈何不了我们
Can't hurt us much out there, bobbing about like that.
先不着急呼叫舰长
No need to call the captain yet.
老骨头
Bones.
在
Yes, captain?
我不应该责骂你
I shouldn't have chewed you out.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我理解
I understand.
然而，这样没有效率
Inefficient, however.
感情用事，舰长
Emotion, captain.
你说的很对，史波克先生
Yes, you're quite right, Mr. Spock.
无效…
Inefficient...
…且不合逻辑
...and illogical.
你交出了武器，显示了我们的友好
You've shown friendship by handing over our weapons.
她现在也作出相同的姿态
And she's making a gesture in return.
吉姆
Jim.
如果你碰了
If you touch it,
她最近的男性亲属就要杀了你
her nearest male relative will have to try to kill you.
他们这是给你战斗的机会
They're offering you a chance for combat.
他们认为战斗比爱更具乐趣
They consider it more pleasurable than love.
如果你表现的很失落，他们就会满意
It would appear, captain, that he finds you a disappointment.
我是阿卡王，提尔
I am the Teer, Akaar.
领导科普兰的十个部落
I lead the Ten Tribes of Capella.
这是依琳
And this is Eleen.
我年轻的妻子
A young wife,
即将诞下我的子嗣，延续我的统治
to give an old man a son to rule these tribes.
我是寇克舰长
I'm Captain Kirk.
首先，我必须对我手下船员的死亡表示抗议
First, I must protest the killing of one of my crewmen.
那是你的船员，为你而死不是他的荣幸吗？
If it was your man, was it not his privilege to die for you?
- 我不理解 - 他们的风俗和我们不同，提尔
- I do not understand. - Their customs are different, Teer.
也和我们的不同，提尔
And different from those of my people too, Teer.
他们惧怕死亡
The sight of death frightens them.
让我来，吉姆
Let me take this, Jim.
马布说的没错
What Maab has said is true.
我们的风俗不同
Our customs are different.
克林贡人所说的不重要
What the Klingon has said is unimportant,
我们不愿听他所说的
and we do not hear his words.
我刚才说克林贡人是骗子
I just called the Klingon a liar.
可笑吗，提尔？
Laughter, Teer?
克林贡人不也是我们尊贵的客人？
Is not the Klingon an honoured guest also?
地球人是第一个出价购买我们的石头的
It is the Earth people who first bargained for our rocks.
对我们来说，难道不是两方出价购买同样的东西更好吗？
Is it not best to have two who bargain for the same goods?
- 我代表部落发言，马布 - 我代表多数人发言，提尔
- It is I who speak for the tribe, Maab. - I speak for many, Teer.
听听克林贡人怎么说
Hear the words of the Klingon.
地球人向你们提供什么？
What do Earthmen offer you?
过去你们从他们那里得到了什么？
What have you obtained from them in the past?
治疗疾病的粉末和药水？
Powders and liquids for the sick?
克林贡人和你们一样
We Klingons believe as you do.
都认为生病的人就应该死
The sick should die.
只有强者才能生存
Only the strong should live.
地球人承诺教授你们部落的年轻人很多东西
Earthmen have promised to teach the youth of your tribes many things.
那么究竟是什么东西？
What? What things?
抵御敌人的小聪明？
Cleverness against enemies?
- 如何使用武器？ - 克林贡人说的没错，阿卡王
- The use of weapons? - The Klingon speaks the truth, Akaar.
地球联盟还提供了另外一样东西，阿卡王
The Earth Federation offers one other thing, Akaar.
我们的律法，我们律法中的最高原则是
Our laws. And the highest of all our laws states:
你们的世界，一直都是你们的
Your world is yours, and will always remain yours.
这是我们和克林贡人不同的地方
This differs us from the Klingons.
他们的帝国因征服世界而组成
Their empire is made up of conquered worlds.
他们用军队和武力夺走想要的一切
They take what they want by arms and force.
很好
Good.
就让克林贡人和地球人在这里娱乐大家吧
Let the Klingons and the Earthmen offer us amusement.
科普兰人喜欢这些
Capellans welcome this.
地球人的风俗与我们不同
The Earthmen have different customs.
但是他们从来没对我们撒谎过
But never have they lied to our people.
我们有些人不愿与地球人做交易，阿卡王
There are those of us who will not bargain with Earthmen, Akaar.
你这是要挑战我吗，马布？
Do you say you will fight me, Maab?
您来选，提尔
Let that be your choice, Teer.
我们需要通讯设备
We need our communicators, those devices on our belts.
如果这附近有克林贡人的飞船…
If there's a Klingon ship somewhere...
我们不关心天空
The sky does not interest me.
我要考虑一番
I must consider the words I have heard.
退下吧
Leave him.
那艘飞船消失了，超出范围了
The ship's disappeared, sir. Gone out of range.
史考特先生，我收到来自一艘飞船的呼叫
Mr. Scott, I'm getting a call from a vessel.
信号很弱，无法辨认
So faint I can't make it out.
用放大器试一下，看能不能捕捉到
Put a booster on it, Lieutenant. Try to pull it in.
没有了
I've lost it.
感觉像是来自地球飞船的求救信号
It sounded like a distress signal from an Earth vessel.
克林贡人！
Klingon!
通讯设备，还有武器
Communicators. Weapons.
我和你们没有争端，舰长，只是希望…
I have no quarrel with you, captain. I wish merely to...
返回我们的飞船
...return to my vessel.
飞船类型是什么？位置在哪里？
Type of vessel? Location?
一艘小型侦查船，舰长
A small scout ship, captain.
我们也需要矿物
We need the mineral too.
我是被派来谈判的
I was sent to negotiate.
放开他
Release him.
阿卡已经死了
Akaar is dead.
现在我是提尔王
I am the Teer.
- 杀了他们 - 等等！
- Kill them now. - Wait!
如果你做人们的领袖，一定要做出正确的选择
If you lead these people now, be certain you make the right decisions.
十个部落的新领袖怕了吗？
Is the new leader of the Ten Tribes afraid?
- 让我帮你杀了他们 - 或者让我和克林贡人决斗
- Let me kill them for you. - Or let the Klingon and me fight.
你就当看热闹了
It might amuse you.
也许，作为提尔王就是要用新眼光看待事物
Perhaps to be a Teer is to see in new ways.
我开始喜欢你了，地球人
I begin to like you, Earthman.
我在克林贡人的眼里看到了恐惧
And I saw fear in the Klingon's eye.
我们有协议的
We had an agreement.
协议也可以变，克林贡人
That too, may change, Klingon.
史考特先生，可以收到清晰信号了 是求救信号
I have the signal clear now, Mr. Scott. It is a distress call.
来自迪尔德丽号
It's from the SS Dierdre.
迪尔德丽号是运输舰
Dierdre. That's a freighter.
他们遭到了攻击，在逃跑，试图想办法摆脱敌人
Reporting they're under attack. They're running, trying to manoeuvre.
是克林贡人飞船在攻击他们
It's a Klingon vessel attacking.
- 荷尔姆？ - 收到，长官，正在修改航向
- Helm? - Picking it up, sir. Taking a fix.
呼叫舰长
Try the captain.
进取号呼叫寇克舰长，收到请回答
Enterprise to Captain Kirk. Come in, captain.
舰长，小心
Captain, careful.
- 你怀的孩子会成为提尔王 - 我难逃一死
- You carry a child who would be Teer. - I must die.
不！
No!
男人不可触碰提尔王的妻子
No man may touch the wife of a Teer.
她准备好受死了，地球人
She was prepared to die, Earthman.
我一直为自己遵守法律而骄傲
I was proud to obey the laws.
先杀了他
Kill him first.
他碰了我
He laid hands upon me.
我有权看着他死
It is my right to see him die.
进取号呼叫史波克
Enterprise to Mr. Spock.
麦考伊医生，请回答
Dr. McCoy, come in please.
传感器上可以看到，上尉，传送到我的频道
I have it on the sensors, sir. Tie into my channel, lieutenant.
已传送
Tied in.
…我们遭到了来自克林贡飞船的猛烈攻击
... commanding. We are under heavy attack by Klingon vessels.
两艘护卫舰已损毁
Two convoy ships are already damaged.
请务必提供援助，进取号，收到请回复
We must have help. Enterprise, acknowledge.
收到请回复…
Please acknowledge. Repeat...
已重新计算拦截航线并导入，长官
Interception course computed and laid in, sir.
准备驶离轨道，苏鲁先生
Prepare to take us out of orbit, Mr. Sulu.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
史考特，舰长还…
Scotty, the captain...
有一艘联邦星舰遭到了攻击，向我们发出求救信号
We have a distress call from a Federation ship under attack.
这是我们的职责所在
That's where our duty lies.
苏鲁，驶离轨道，曲速5前进
Take us out of orbit, Mr. Sulu. Ahead warp 5.
舰长日志，星历3498.9
Captain's log, stardate 3498.9.
史考特少校暂任指挥官
Lieutenant Commander Scott in temporary command.
我们被迫离开科普兰星球，前去营救一艘
We were forced to leave Capella to come to the aid of a Federation vessel
正遭受克林贡人攻击的联邦星舰
under attack by a Klingon vessel.
回应求救信号之前
We were unable to contact our landing party
我们无法与地面派遣小组取得联系
before we were forced to answer the distress signal.
无法与地面派遣小组取得联系很是蹊跷
Our inability to reach the landing party is strange,
我很担心
and I am concerned.
我们的回舰信号已经发出1小时12分钟了，还没有回复…
Our check-in signal is one hour 12 minutes overdue.
鉴于没有侦察小组出现
Since no reconnaissance party has appeared,
鉴于史考特先生在这方面总是十分高效…
and since Mr. Scott is notably efficient in such matters...
可以确定一定是有什么事让他抽不开身
I must assume that something's keeping them busy up there.
克林贡飞船
The Klingon ship.
这个结论很合理
That would seem a logical conclusion.
舰长…
Captain...
我得治好那女人的胳膊
...l'm gonna fix that woman's arm.
我碰了她，他们也只能杀我一次
They can only kill me once for touching her.
好主意，老骨头
That's a very good idea, Bones.
没错，舰长，这主意很棒
Yes, captain. An excellent idea.
让我看看那只胳膊
Let me see that arm.
你不能碰我
You will not touch me.
你之前说自己准备好赴死了
You said you were prepared to die.
难道说你更愿意活着？
Does that mean you prefer to die?
回到星舰我们就可以保证你的安全，少校你自己来选
I think we can get you safely to the ship. Your choice.
活着总是更吸引人
To live is always desirable.
很好，走吧
All right, let's go.
克林贡
Klingon.
那边没什么需要你担心的
There is nothing to concern you there.
我们有协议，马布，我有权掌握自己的武器
We made an agreement, Maab. I have a right to my weapons.
我们会好好保管的，克林贡
We have them well cared for, Klingon.
等我们的生意谈妥了，就会还给你
Your weapon will be returned when our business is completed.
这才是我们的协议
That was our agreement.
后部相位炮已准备好，即将进入舰桥
Aft phaser, affirmative. We're going to bridge.
接近运输舰的最后报告位置，长官
Approaching the freighter's last reported position, sir.
传感器报告，契诃夫？
Sensor report, Mr. Chekov?
没有，长官，没有残骸，没有遗留物
Negative, sir. No debris, no residual particles.
毫无痕迹
No traces.
苏鲁先生，启动标准搜索程序
Mr. Sulu, begin a standard search pattern.
开启全部扫描仪，契诃夫
All scanners full intensity, Mr. Chekov.
- 没有信号？ - 没有
- No signal at all? - Negative, sir.
现在应该已经在显示器上了
It should be on our screens by now.
运输舰的最大速度不过曲速2
At best a freighter might travel warp two.
我很清楚运输舰的最大速度，苏鲁先生
I'm well aware of a freighter's maximum speed, Mr. Sulu.
舰长日志，星历3499.1
Captain's log, stardate 3499.1.
离开科普兰营地之前
Before leaving the Capellan encampment,
我们设法拿到了通讯设备
we managed to retrieve our communicators.
但是没有找到相位枪
Our phasers were not to be found.
我们逃到了山丘地带，但是科普兰人
We have fled into the hills, yet we know the Capellans will eventually find us
最终根据气味会找到我们
by scent alone, if necessary.
我们知道了另外一件事
And we have learned one thing more.
这个叫伊莲的女孩，恨她腹中未出生的孩子
The girl, Eleen, hates the unborn child she is carrying.
老骨头，陪着她
Stay with her, Bones.
真是个瓮中捉鳖的好地方
Nice place to get trapped in.
但是也易守难攻啊，舰长
But a defensible entrance, captain.
没错
Yes, I see.
去看看那条路，看能不能找到出口
Scout up the trail that way. See what we have in the way of an exit.
我查看一下周围环境
I'll take a look around.
听我说，就算你是科普兰女人
Now listen, you may be a Capellan woman
就算你是提尔王的妻子
and the widow of a High Teer.
但我是医生，救死扶伤是我的职责
But I'm a doctor, and it's my tradition to care for the sick and injured.
让我看看你的胳膊
Now let me see that arm.
- 你不能这么碰我 - 你给我听好了，年轻的女士
- You will not touch me in that manner. - Now you listen to me, young woman.
我的专业判断需要我怎么碰你，我就怎么碰你
I'll touch you in any way or manner that my professional judgement indicates.
跟我想的一样
Just as I thought.
随时可能分娩
It can come any time now.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
我是医生，怎么会不知道
Because I'm a doctor, that's how I know.
村子里的女人都不可能碰一下就知道这么多
Even the women of our village cannot tell so much with a touch.
真是只奇怪的手
Strange hand.
这么柔软
Very soft.
山石越来越高，山路越来越窄，但是有条路可以出去
The walls get higher and narrower, but there is a way out.
很好
Good.
要是等堵住入口，可以争取更多时间
If we could block off that entrance, it'd give us more time.
- 他们得绕过这些山 - 这里的石头还有页岩很松
- They'd have to go around these hills. - There's enough loose rock and shale.
我们可以用两台通讯设备
Do you think we could create a sonic disruption
造成音波破坏
with two of our communicators?
成功的几率很小
Only a very slight chance it would work.
要是你觉得不行，那就别试了
Well, if you don't think we can, maybe we shouldn't try.
我没有这么说
I didn't say that exactly.
声波束会使那边山石的
Sound beams should produce a sympathetic vibration...
疏松区域产生共振
...on the weak area of that slide.
担心会随时分娩？
Worried about the delivery?
科普兰人不是人类，吉姆，他们是类人物种
Capellans aren't human, Jim. They're humanoid.
身体内部构造是有区别的
There are certain internal differences.
我没有应付紧急情况所需的工具
I don't have the equipment to handle an emergency.
- 你要是觉得自己不行… - 算了，我可以的
- If you don't think you can handle it... - Forget it. I can do it.
最不需要的就是身边有个笨手笨脚的舰长
The last thing I want around is a ham-handed ship's captain.
不行！只有麦考伊可以
No! Only McCoy.
那边有个洞，可能是这附近唯一的庇护
There's a cave in there. Probably the only shelter around here.
我需要人帮我扶着她
I'll need help getting her in there.
不行！
No!
我是医生，不是自动扶梯，史波克，帮帮我
Look, I'm a doctor, not an escalator. Spock! Give me a hand!
我只允许你碰我
I will allow only your touch.
飞船不会无故消失
A vessel doesn't just disappear.
什么都没有，史考特先生 所有频道所有频率都试过了
There's nothing, Mr. Scott. All channels and frequencies are clear.
契诃夫先生？
Mr. Chekov?
什么都没有
Nothing, sir.
如果是被摧毁了，肯定能够发现残骸
If it were destroyed, I'd pick up debris readings of some sort.
也不可能超过我们，毕竟是艘运输舰
It couldn't have run away from us, sir. Not a freighter.
契诃夫先生，再放一遍求救信号的带子
Mr. Chekov, pull the microtape on that distress call. I want it replayed.
…我们遭到了克林贡飞船的攻击
... commanding. We are under heavy attack by Klingon vessels.
两艘护卫舰已损毁
Two convoy ships are already damaged.
请务必援助，进取号，收到请回复
We must have help! Enterprise, acknowledge.
- 收到请回复 - 听到了吗？
- Please acknowledge. - Did you hear it?
它指明了我们
They called us by name.
不是一般的求救信号，而是针对我们的
Not a general distress signal, but one aimed right at us.
一般都会向最近的星舰求救
Wouldn't they normally call for the nearest starship?
一艘运输舰怎么会知道我们在这一区域执行任务？
How would a freighter know we were ordered into this sector?
陷阱
Trap.
调虎离山
We were diverted from the planet.
也可能真的是求救信号
Or it could be an authentic distress call.
我们会搞清楚的
We'll stay long enough to make certain.
- 继续搜索程序 - 是，长官
- Continue search pattern. - Yes, sir. Continuing.
老骨头？
Bones?
你的工具袋里还有硝酸菱镁片吗？
You've got one of those magnesite-nitron tablets in your kit.
- 给我一个 - 等一下
- Give me one. - Just a minute.
我先让她坐下
Let me get her on the rock.
这里疼
Pain is here.
你是怎么可以碰她的？给她吃镇定剂了？
How did you arrange to touch her, Bones? Give her a happy pill?
不是，用右吊拳
No. Right cross.
- 医典里面可没写这个啊 - 从此以后就写在我的医典里了
- Never seen that in a medical book. - It's in mine from now on.
不是，在那里
No, it's there.
那里疼
Pain is there.
植物，舰长，看来附近有水
Vegetation, captain. Evidently there's water nearby.
很好，但是我们还需要武器，就像需要水一样
Good. But we need weapons just as much as we need water, Spock.
很快就会有武器了
There would seem to be little weapon potential at hand.
跟我来
Follow me.
麦考伊！
McCoy!
别怕，我在这儿
Easy. I'm here.
你得要这个孩子
You must want the child.
不
No.
在这里，孩子属于丈夫
Here child belongs to husband.
这么说什么都是他们的，明摆着的！
So they take all the credit here. Poppycock!
告诉我，你想让我帮你吗？
Answer me. Do you want my help?
很好
All right.
告诉自己，“这孩子是我的”
Say to yourself, "The child is mine.
这孩子是我的，是我的
The child is mine. It is mine."
没错，是你的
Yes. It's yours.
不是，不是这样的
No. You've got it all wrong.
没错，麦考伊
Yes, McCoy.
是你的
It's yours.
不是，你要对自己说，“这孩子是我的”
No. Say to yourself, "The child is mine.
是我的，是…
It is mine. It is..."
寇克呼叫进取号，请回答
Kirk to Enterprise. Come in.
幸好这树皮拉伸聚合性很好
Fortunately this bark has suitable tensile cohesion.
你是说做弓弦很合适？
You mean it makes a good bow string?
我就是这么说的
I believe I said that.
这才像话
That's more like it.
既然科普兰人不会做弓箭
Since the Capellans never developed the bow,
这会让他们大吃一惊的，就像地球上的火药一样
this may come as big a surprise as gunpowder was on Earth.
不对，史波克，这样不对
No, Mr. Spock. That isn't the way.
这只胳膊放下面，支撑背部
You place this arm under here to support its back,
这只放这里，抱住头部
and this hand here, to support its head.
我还是算了吧，谢谢你
I would rather not, thank you.
麦考伊
McCoy.
把我们的孩子抱过来
Bring our child.
“我们的”孩子？
"Our" child?
- 我待会儿解释？ - 估计会很有意思
- I'll explain later. - That should prove very interesting.
还是没有，史考特先生，干干净净
Still negative, Mr. Scott. All sweeps.
- 契诃夫先生？ - 什么都没有
- Mr. Chekov? - Nothing.
- 准备返回，曲速5，舵手 - 曲速5，长官
- We're turning back. Warp five, helm. - Warp five, sir.
返回科普兰IV
On course for Capella IV.
如果可以的话，提速到曲速6
Warp 6 as soon as she'll take it, Mr. Sulu.
舰长可能有麻烦
The captain could be in trouble back there.
史考特先生，收到来自联邦星舰卡罗莱纳号的求救信号
Mr. Scott. Another distress call from the USS Carolina.
忽略它
Ignore it.
史考特先生，卡罗莱纳号确实是在这一区域登记的
Mr. Scott, the Carolina is registered in this sector.
忽略它，上尉，有问题我来负责
Ignore it, lieutenant. Log it as my order, my responsibility.
是，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
史考特，万一是真的…
Scotty, if it should turn out to be real...
地球上有句俗话，苏鲁先生
There's an old, old saying on Earth, Mr. Sulu:
“骗我一次，你可耻，骗我两次，是我笨”
"Fool me once, shame on you. Fool me twice, shame on me."
我听过，这句话源自俄罗斯
I know this saying. It was invented in Russia.
吉姆！
Jim!
史波克！
Spock!
吉姆！史波克！
Jim! Spock!
怎么了，老骨头？
What happened, Bones?
我的病人用石头砸晕我，自己跑了
My patient spattered me with a rock. She's gone.
- 孩子呢？ - 他很好，这这里
- The child? - It's all right. It's in there.
看来我忘记了精神疗法，只关注了手术
I guess I'll forget psychiatry, stick with surgery.
- 我真的以为她是真心想要 - 美德是一个相对的概念，医生
- I really thought she'd learn to want it. - Virtue is a relative term, Doctor.
- 她会直接去找那些战士 - 我和你一起去
- She'll head straight to the warriors. - I'll go with you.
早在登上进取号之前你就已经发下了医德誓言
You took a medical oath long before you signed aboard my ship.
那里还有个小病人需要你
That small patient in there needs you.
- 评估一下这个星球？ - 31分钟，长官
- Estimating the planet? - Thirty-one minutes, sir.
扫描仪呼叫舰桥，请讲，引擎控制
Scanner to Bridge. Read. Engineering control.
史考特先生
Mr. Scott.
传感器上显示有飞船朝我们的方向飞来
Sensors picking up a vessel ahead.
挡住了我们的去路
Cutting across our path.
- 亚光速前进 - 调整至一半光速
- Sub-light, one half. - Reversing to sub-light. One half.
是外星人，长官
It's an alien, sir.
据分析，是一艘克林贡战舰
By configuration, a Klingon warship.
正朝我们的方向来
Taking position directly in our path.
- 苏鲁，发出战斗警报 - 是，长官
- Mr. Sulu, sound battle stations. - Aye, aye, sir.
联邦星舰进取号呼叫克林贡飞船，请回答
This is the USS Enterprise calling unidentified Klingon vessel. Come in.
联邦星舰进取号呼叫克林贡飞船，收到请回答
USS Enterprise calling Klingon vessel. Acknowledge, please.
屏幕上可以看到了，长官，还很远
I have it on the viewscreen now, sir. Still distant.
位于我们的正前方，长官
Holding a position dead ahead, sir.
划清界限，警告对方不要越过
Drawing a line, daring us to step over it.
还在接近
Still closing.
对方直接朝我们的航线飞来
The alien is directly in our line of flight.
我是联邦星舰进取号的指挥官
This is the commander of the USS Enterprise.
亮明你方身份及目的
Identify yourself and your intention.
完毕
Acknowledge.
关掉频率，上尉
Close out the frequency, lieutenant.
相位炮准备就绪，长官
Phaser banks are ready, sir.
如果有必要，我们就直捣对方心脏
And we'll go right down their throat, if necessary.
看看他们胆量
Let's see if they have the belly for it.
在上面的石头后面
Behind the rocks up there.
地球人很会玩游戏
The Earthmen make excellent game.
他们的聪明让我惊讶
Their cleverness has surprised me.
他们非死不可
They must die.
这是你们的律法
That is your law.
我们尊崇自己的法律，也会信守诺言，克林贡人
We will honour our law and our word to you, Klingon.
马布
Maab.
那孩子死了，马布
The child is dead, Maab.
正如我也会死在你手里
Do as you will with me.
地球人呢？
The Earthmen?
死了
Dead.
我趁他们睡觉时杀了他们
I killed them as they slept.
如果你说的是真的，带我们去看看
If true, take us to them.
你怀疑我，克林贡人？
Do you doubt my word, Klingon?
我是提尔王之妻
I am the wife of a Teer.
我会死在自己的帐篷里
I will die in my own tent.
这合乎规矩，她的确是提尔王之妻
It is in order. She is the wife of a Teer.
不行！我们要先证实她的话
No! First we verify her story!
这就是你所说的信守诺言吗，克林贡人？
Is this what your sworn word means, Klingon?
史波克？
Spock?
这里，舰长
Here, captain.
这边，舰长
Over here, captain.
史波克呼叫进取号
Spock to Enterprise.
不会再有千钧一发时突然出现的骑兵了
The cavalry doesn't come over the hill in the nick of time any more.
如果你是说我们没法指望进取号的支援，我同意
If by that you mean we can't expect help from the Enterprise, I must agree.
我只想要一样东西
There's just one thing I want.
克林贡人？
The Klingon?
我们中有一人得抓住他
One of us must get him.
复仇吗？
Revenge, captain?
有何不可？
Why not?
再有人敢拿起武器，你们全都必死无疑
The next man who raises a weapon destroys all of you.
你们，还有你们的原始武器
You and your primitive knives and your weapons!
我会让你们见识见识什么是真正的杀戮
I'll teach you what killing really means.
克林贡！
Klingon!
打啊！
Fight!
你们是战士还是孩子？
Are you warriors or children?
马布，我会逃走的
Maab. I will flee.
等到克林贡人开火的时候，我会…
When the Klingon turns to fire, I'll...
身为十个部落的提尔王，我赦免你
As Teer of the Ten Tribes, I give you back your life.
而我的生命到此为止
Mine is now forfeit.
基尔，准备好
Keel, stand ready.
克林贡人！
Klingon!
别动！放下武器！
Hold it there! Drop your weapons!
我们很想念你，史考特先生
We missed you, Mr. Scott.
我们去追了一下克林贡飞船
We had a wee bit of a run-in with a Klingon vessel
但是无意恋战
but he had no stomach for fighting.
我们检查过营地，发现你们在那里逗留过
We checked the encampment, found out you were here
然后就一路追到了这里，我可以…
and had no trouble at all in tracking you down. I could...
不对，不是这样抱的，像这样
No, that's not the way to handle it. Here, like this.
这只手抱住头部
Here, take its little head like that.
胳膊放下面，就这样，很容易吧？
There. Arm under, that's it. See how easy?
“呜哧呜哧呜哧”？
"Oochy-woochy-kootchy-coo," captain?
一种很晦涩的地球方言，史波克先生
An obscure Earth dialect, Mr. Spock.
想知道的话可以查查语言学相关著作
If you're curious, consult linguistics.
想来会很有意思
At any rate, this should prove interesting.
有意思？
Interesting?
那女人开始解释新的提尔王
When the woman starts explaining how the new High Teer
怎么会是麦考伊医生的孩子的时候
is actually Dr. McCoy's child.
什么，史波克先生？
What's that again, Mr. Spock?
我们也不是很懂自己，史考特
We don't actually understand it ourselves, Mr. Scott.
麦考伊也不懂
Nor does Dr. McCoy.
联络星际舰队
Contact Starfleet.
通知他们星际联邦在科普兰星的
Inform them that Federation mining rights on Capella
采矿权已有协议保障
have been secured by treaty.
文件已由新首领的摄政王签署
Documents signed by the young High Chief's regent.
- 详细报告稍后发回 - 是，长官
- Report follows. - Aye, aye, sir.
- 摄政王？ - 没错，伊莲，一位了不起的年轻女士
- The child's regent? - Yes. Eleen. A remarkable young lady.
代表新的提尔王
Representing the High Teer,
伦纳德·詹姆士·阿卡
Leonard James Akaar.
那孩子叫做伦纳德·詹姆士·阿卡？
The child was named Leonard James Akaar?
朗朗上口，对吧，詹姆士？
Has a kind of a ring to it, don't you think, James?
我觉得这名字会名垂青史，伦纳德
I think it's a name destined to go down in galactic history, Leonard.
- 你觉得怎么样，史波克？ - 我觉得这个事情
- What do you think, Spock? - I think you're both gonna be
可以让两位开心至少一个月，长官
insufferably pleased with yourselves for at least a month, sir.
驶离轨道，苏鲁先生，以曲速一前进
Take us out of orbit, Mr. Sulu. Ahead, warp factor one.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF微博http://weibo.com/tlfsubs/
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/